nrcc.org 2014-04-11

# Privacy Policy - National Republican Congressional Committee www.nrcc.org

Welcome to the official Web site of the National Republican Congressional Committee. The NRCC knows your right to privacy is important, especially online. This privacy policy has been created to answer any questions you may have regarding the NRCC’s data collection and protection policies.

**What information is being collected at[www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/)?**

The only personal information collected is information you give us. In an effort to grow our Republican grassroots community online, the NRCC may ask you to submit information. This information will be used to provide you with information about online events, personal appearances, TV appearances, talking points, and other Republican related information. You do not have to provide this information – we only ask that you do so that we can better communicate with you! Additionally, when you offer your personal information and/or choose to participate in our volunteer efforts, we use your information to personalize and customize Web pages and emails from the NRCC to you. We may also use the information to credit individuals for their actions in support of the NRCC and Republican congressional candidates. We’re thankful for your support, and we want to recognize you! Some information must be collected when you make a contribution. When you make contributions to the NRCC that aggregate to more than $200 in a single election cycle, federal law requires us to use our “best efforts” to collect your name, mailing address, employer, and occupation. Credit card information provided may be stored at the donor’s option. In the event a donor exercises that option, all credit card information will be stored with the NRCC’s secure third party vendor, certified to PCI Service Provider Level 1, the most stringent level of certification. Any information shared is done at the donor’s own risk.

We ask that children under 18 do not submit their information. In accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), [www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/) does not knowingly collect information from children. In accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), the NRCC will never knowingly collect personal identifiable information from persons thirteen years old or younger.

**How is the information collected at[www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/) used?**

We will not sell your personal information. Under no circumstances will the NRCC sell your information to third parties or any commercial entities. The NRCC may share information — that you voluntarily provide us — with like-minded organizations committed to the principles or candidates of the Republican Party, Republican State Party organizations and local Republican groups. The NRCC may provide your email address or other personal information to authorized third parties required to deliver a particular service. These third parties may not use said information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for the NRCC.

**Is my information secure?**

Protecting information you provide is important to us. The NRCC makes every effort to protect your information from the moment you enter your information to when it is stored on our secure servers. [www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/) uses a secure socket layer (SSL) – with the highest level of encryption commercially available – on pages where online visitors register or make a secure online donation using their credit card. Strict security measures are in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of any and all information pertaining to [www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/). [www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/) uses a secured/encrypted server for online credit card donations. The online contribution form is in compliance with FEC regulations. The NRCC has put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to prevent unauthorized access.

[www.NRCC.org](http://www.nrcc.org/) links to other sites: Our site may contain links to other websites and servers. The NRCC does not bear responsibility for privacy policies or content on linked websites. Because the NRCC has no control over the websites we link to, you agree and acknowledge that the NRCC is not responsible for the availability of resources or external sites and does not endorse and is not responsible or liable for any content provided therein. Accordingly, you also agree and acknowledge that the NRCC will not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance of any such content, services on or through any such site or resource or goods. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on each website you visit. The NRCC provides links to original articles written and maintained by third parties. These links are provided as a convenience and do not imply a claim of ownership in that content.

**How do I contact the National Republican Congressional Committee?**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns please contact the NRCC by e-mail or by phone using the contact information [provided here](http://www.nrccdev.org/contact-us/ "Contact Us").

**Will this privacy policy change?**

We have no intentions to make changes to this privacy policy, though we do reserve the right to revise or update this privacy policy at any time.

**3 rd Party Advertising Cookies Opt-Out**

The National Republican Congressional Committee is dedicated to providing privacy on the Internet.  In addition to developing our privacy policy, we have provided you the opportunity to opt out of future 3rd party advertising cookies.

**The NRCC** **** allows third parties to place cookies on our site for advertising purposes.  This Online Privacy Statement does not cover the collection methods or use of the information collected by these vendors. These vendors have their own privacy policies and may be members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) (“NAI”).  To remove yourself from some or all NAI member advertising programs, please visit the [NAI Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and follow the relevant instructions.  Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we or a data provider we have engaged may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads or content.   These cookies contain no personally identifiable information.  The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies, please go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.
